<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programmer on nauval atmaja</title>
    <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/tags/programmer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programmer on nauval atmaja</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 20:47:09 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://nauvalatmaja.com/tags/programmer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to be a Programmer</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/02/28/time-to-be-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 20:47:09 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/02/28/time-to-be-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://nauvalatmaja.com/img/kids-code.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kid who codes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indonesian tech startups are gaining momentum in recent years as more VCs
are investing into local startups. Big names such as Sequoia Capital have entered the country by funding
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinasia.com/tokopedia-softbank-sequoia-capital-funding-news#!&#34;&gt;Tokopedia (together with SoftBank)&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinasia.com/indonesia-sequoia-go-jek&#34;&gt;Gojek&lt;/a&gt;.
Chinese VCs also getting more
active too. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techinasia.com/moxybilna-raises-15-million-is-now-called-orami&#34;&gt;Gobi partners latest investment on Oramy (former MoxyBilna)&lt;/a&gt;
is a proof to the statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it means they pursue growth more than ever. To sustain the required growth
rate, they need to grow as well, in term of size and organization. Hence, they need a lot of people to fill bunch of positions and software
developer/programmer are one
of the most highlighted one. Based on the insider rumours, some startups
even planning to double their engineering team in the near future to cope
with their growth.
Why? because they are &lt;em&gt;tech&lt;/em&gt; companies that
leverage technologies to solve costumers&amp;rsquo; problems and most of the used
technologies are computer-based software, which is relatively easier to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being in high demand, programmers are scarcely available. Currently
we have under supply of programmers situation, at least based on my
observation and experience on seeking and interviewing programmers for
software developer role. So, it is a common sight when a startup hijacks
other startups&amp;rsquo; programmers to join the team, which also come with a
significant amount of compensation and additional benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A decade ago, a computer-science-related graduate in Indonesia
would see telco,
banking and oil &amp;amp; gas industries as the top career paths to pursue to make
a good living. However, now there&amp;rsquo;s an alternative to those: startups.
An experienced programmer in a startup could earn relatively same
(or maybe even more) to those who work in those industries, especially
big name startups with lot of investment funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the wages, there are a lot of perks when working in a startup.
Dealing with new cool technologies is one of it. Personally this is the
very reason I decided to work in a startup a year ago. Being a programmer
in a corporate is very restraining, way too rigid. There are a lot of
efforts to put when wanting to implement new technologies, even more, most of the efforts are wasted to non-technical issues, bureaucracy. In contrast,
in startups programmers are always in search of new technologies available
to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, startups culture is almost the opposite of corporates&amp;rsquo;,
more freedom and less bureaucracy. Usually startups have flatter
organizational structure. Which means it is easier to communicate to everyone
else including the CEO. This is particularly important during product development.
We don&amp;rsquo;t need to set an official meeting just to ask view questions to let&amp;rsquo;s say sales or operation team about our product, efficiency. For the freedom part, at the very least employees are
free to wear T-shirts to the office, some of them even work remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, most startups are merit base system, they see what we capable of instead of our formal education background or anything else. It means
everyone can be a programmer if s/he wants to. Being in high demand, it
is undeniably very good opportunities to anyone to enter the industry
as a programmer, given the aforementioned benefits. However, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know computer programming right now but aspire to be a
programmer in the future (or even just for fun), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecademy.com/&#34;&gt;Codeacademy&lt;/a&gt; could be a
good place to start, or if you want to be in an after work coding
class, you might want to check &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gepi.co/coding-class&#34;&gt;GEPI Coding Class&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, is this the right time to be a programmer in Indonesia?
yes it is, and always is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[photo credit]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A-2-year-old using a MacBook. Photo taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://danq.me/2014/09/28/kids-code/&#34;&gt;danq.me&lt;/a&gt;, Photograph copyright
Donnie Ray Jones, used under Creative Commons license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>