<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nauval atmaja</title>
    <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nauval atmaja</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 15:18:16 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://nauvalatmaja.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Self Contained Go Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2017/12/31/a-self-contained-go-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 15:18:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2017/12/31/a-self-contained-go-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>Go(lang) is getting momentum in Indonesia during the recent years as big names are migrating to Go. Tokopedia, Go-Jek, I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you both. Not to mention many other startups build their tech-stack using Go from the get-go due to the hype.
Go is an interesting programming language, not to mention it has fun part in it. It combines the ease of dynamically typed language and the efficiency of statically typed language with support for networked and multicore computing (Go FAQ page, 2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Vim</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2017/05/28/going-vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 09:18:16 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2017/05/28/going-vim/</guid>
      <description>Vim or &amp;ldquo;Vi Improved&amp;rdquo; is a text editor that works in every terminal. Some people even consider Vim as the best text editor for programming. However, many people are also intimidated with its steep learning curve. Vim is a terminal-based text editor which means everything are operated through keyboard keys, there is no need to use the trackpad or mouse. This is actually what makes Vim powerful. One does not need to take their fingers off of the keyboard when writing in Vim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Function Composition in Go</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/04/15/function-composition-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 07:40:17 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/04/15/function-composition-in-go/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with functional JavaScript for a while, especially partial applications and function composition, and I find those concepts are very helpful in my daily coding practices. At first, if you are short in mathematical logic systems (just like me), making sense anything functional could be a bit out of hand. Fortunately there are a lot of reading materials that do a great job explaining the concepts in an easy and pragmatic way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to be a Programmer</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/02/28/time-to-be-a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 20:47:09 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/02/28/time-to-be-a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Indonesian tech startups are gaining momentum in recent years as more VCs are investing into local startups. Big names such as Sequoia Capital have entered the country by funding Tokopedia (together with SoftBank) and Gojek. Chinese VCs also getting more active too. Gobi partners latest investment on Oramy (former MoxyBilna) is a proof to the statement.
Now, it means they pursue growth more than ever. To sustain the required growth rate, they need to grow as well, in term of size and organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Learning to Code</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/01/17/on-learning-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 20:20:12 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/01/17/on-learning-to-code/</guid>
      <description>My friend at office asked me recently &amp;ldquo;Can I learn to code by myself?&amp;rdquo;. You may have probably encountered one or two posts that talk about it elsewhere. And they point to the same answer as mine: &amp;ldquo;yes you can&amp;rdquo;. As a background, I receive a formal education in Information System (which had less computer science-related courses than computer science or informatics major) and it&amp;rsquo;s past a decade when I wrote my first Hello World!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to Hugo</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/12/27/moving-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:30:28 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/12/27/moving-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Several weeks ago, my Docpad installation got screwed. There was some errors when I tried to run it. My assumption was because I just moved to Node.js 5.x, so I tried to upgrade (or re-install it, maybe) it. Though the errors are gone, it did not work as it used to be, it failed to build my blog properly &amp;mdash; or I just forgotten how to use it, that&amp;rsquo;s another possibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways to Boost Coding Productivity</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/04/09/ways-to-boost-coding-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/04/09/ways-to-boost-coding-productivity/</guid>
      <description>As a someone who codes frequently, in daily basis in fact, I need an environment that is able to boost my productivity when coding. Some might argue that one could be productive in every given environment. That is the ideal case, however live is not. Hence, productivity tools and workflows are created.
During my coding adventure, I found some ways that help me to boost up my productivity, which are listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload Files with Backbone.js, Node.js and express 4.x</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/01/30/upload-files-with-backbone.js-node.js-and-express-4.x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/01/30/upload-files-with-backbone.js-node.js-and-express-4.x/</guid>
      <description>Backbone fundamentals is a great free resource to learn Backbone.js from scratch. The book was written by Addy Osmany under creative-commons license. As its second exercise, the book guide the readers to create a simple library application that uses Node.js as the back-end. However, it left the part to upload book&amp;rsquo;s cover to the readers as an exercise. Hence, here is the way I did it.
Requirement There are two additional requirements for the upload book&amp;rsquo;s cover features: - The selected cover should be previewed as thumbnail</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendering Mermaid in Docpad</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/01/13/rendering-mermaid-in-docpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/01/13/rendering-mermaid-in-docpad/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across Mermaid when I saw @ronaldwidha retweeted a tweet about it. Mermaid is a library for writing diagrams instead of draw them similar to Marked to markdown, awesome! So, I thought I could use this in my blog just in case I need to draw some flowcharts or sequence diagrams in the future.
DocPad uses Marked to render markdown to html via docpad-plugin-marked but natively, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support Mermaid syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Development with Genymotion</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/01/08/android-development-with-genymotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2015/01/08/android-development-with-genymotion/</guid>
      <description>I am a noob in android development and one thing I am not comfortable with is the stock android device emulator. The default emulator is really slow, the boot-up process could take minutes in my machine (I won&amp;rsquo;t say my machine is fast either, but it is sufficient), the app deployment takes too much time, moreover, the interaction is sluggish. Hence, it is a no go.
Up to now, I used my own android phone to test my app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Custom Domain for GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/31/setting-up-custom-domain-for-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/31/setting-up-custom-domain-for-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>It has been a couple days since nauvalatmaja.com is online, and to be honest the process was not as hard as I had imagined. Kudos to David Ensinger who has written in details on how he set up his custom domain for his GitHub pages and tweak it to get faster by using cloudflare. All the needed information to do this can be found there.
I purchased this this domain name at NameCheap, as suggested by David&amp;rsquo;s post, with just a bit more than five bucks for a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rendering Backbone (Sub)View</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/29/rendering-backbone-subview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/29/rendering-backbone-subview/</guid>
      <description>When learning backbone.js (i&amp;rsquo;m a novice by the way), at first, I was actually having a hard time to grasp the backbone view. Especially how the best practice to render the view and build a rather complex view consists of several subviews. And then, magically I came accross Ian Storm Taylor&amp;rsquo;s post about his experience on dealing with backbone subview. At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t quiet understand well about the post until I found a thread on stackoverflow, which was started by Ian Storm Taylor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging with Docpad</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/28/blogging-with-docpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/28/blogging-with-docpad/</guid>
      <description>It has been a long time since I planned to have a dedicated blog for writing about some more &amp;ldquo;meaningful&amp;rdquo; stuff instead of just my rumbling I posted on my trash bin. After looking out what blogging platforms available, I finally decided to use GitHub pages to host my posts. However, as it uses Jekyll as its engine, many people suggested to install Jekyll in my local machine, which was a no-show for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>