<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on nauval atmaja</title>
    <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on nauval atmaja</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 07:40:17 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://nauvalatmaja.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Function Composition in Go</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/04/15/function-composition-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 07:40:17 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/04/15/function-composition-in-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with functional JavaScript for a while, especially partial
applications and function composition, and I find those concepts are very
helpful in my daily coding practices. At first, if you are short in
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_logic&#34;&gt;mathematical logic systems&lt;/a&gt; (just like me), making sense
anything functional could be a bit out of hand. Fortunately there are a lot
of reading materials that do a great job explaining the concepts in an easy and
pragmatic way. You could &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/search?q=functional%20javascript&#34;&gt;search those articles in medium&lt;/a&gt;
and/or you would want to read this &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/javascript-allonge/read&#34;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go, by design is quite different from JavaScript. It is an attempt to combine
the ease of programming of an interpreted, dynamically typed language (e.g., JavaScript) with the efficiency and safety of a statically typed,
compiled language. It also aims to
be modern, with support for networked and multicore computing
(&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/doc/faq#creating_a_new_language&#34;&gt;Go FAQ page&lt;/a&gt;, 2016). However, despite the differences, there are some similarities
between JavaScript and Go, one of them is that they treat
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First-class_function&#34;&gt;functions as first class object&lt;/a&gt;,
which means function is an object that can be passed
around as function&amp;rsquo;s arguments or can be returned from other functions,
and yes, function is a type in Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type fnString func(string) string
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effect of having first-class functions is that we can write Go in a more functional manner, just similar to JavaScript.
In JavaScript we can easily write a &lt;code&gt;compose&lt;/code&gt; function (function to do
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Function_composition_%28computer_science%29&#34;&gt;function composition&lt;/a&gt;) as the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-js&#34;&gt;const compose = (a, b) =&amp;gt; (val) =&amp;gt; a(b(val));

// variadic versions
const compose = (...functions) =&amp;gt;
  (value) =&amp;gt; functions.reverse().reduce((acc, fn) =&amp;gt; fn(acc), value);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Go, as it is a typed language, and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/doc/faq#generics&#34;&gt;it does not support generic type&lt;/a&gt;
per se, first we need to define a type of what the &lt;code&gt;compose&lt;/code&gt; function
will work against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type fnString func(string) string
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, we define &lt;code&gt;fnString&lt;/code&gt; of function type that receives a &lt;code&gt;string&lt;/code&gt;
argument and returns a &lt;code&gt;string&lt;/code&gt;. Next, is to define the &lt;code&gt;compose&lt;/code&gt;
function itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;func compose(a fnString, b fnString) fnString {
	return func(s string) string {
		return a(b(s))
	}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;compose&lt;/code&gt; code is pretty straight forward just like the JavaScript
version. The only main difference is that the function has to comply with the
given type, &lt;code&gt;fnString&lt;/code&gt; in the example above. So if we want to compose functions
that work on other than strings, we might need to define the appropriate type and the appropriate &lt;code&gt;compose&lt;/code&gt; function (as Go does not have generic type),
in contrast to the JavaScript version that will work for all type
&amp;mdash;JavaScript is a dynamic programming language after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, how about the variadic version? Fortunately, Go supports variadic
arguments so it is easier to port the JavaScript code into Go.
However, Go does not
provide direct translation of JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Array.reduce&lt;/code&gt; function, the
only way to compose the functions is by iterating through the passed
functions and compose them one into another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;func compose2(a fnString, b fnString) fnString {
	return func(s string) string {
		return a(b(s))
	}
}

func compose(fns ...fnString) fnString {
	return func(s string) string {
		var res fnString
		res = fns[0]
		for i := 1; i &amp;lt; len(fns); i++ {
			res = compose2(res, fns[i])
		}
		return res(s)
	}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen in the code, the functions are iterated by using for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working example of the above function composition can be seen on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://play.golang.org/p/KUetm5b7zW&#34;&gt;http://play.golang.org/p/KUetm5b7zW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;sectionsign&#34;
  style=&#34;
    margin:0 auto;
    margin-top: -1rem;
    margin-bottom: 1rem;
    text-align: center;
    letter-spacing: 1em;
    color: #333;
  &#34;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;***&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Even though writing Go code in a more functional style is possible, however, Go is not a functional programming language. Hence, I&amp;rsquo;m still not convinced
that writing Go program in a functional manner entirely is a good approach (if that is even possible), but I might be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Learning to Code</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/01/17/on-learning-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 20:20:12 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2016/01/17/on-learning-to-code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My friend at office asked me recently &amp;ldquo;Can I learn to code by myself?&amp;rdquo;. You may have probably encountered
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/search?q=learn%20to%20code&#34;&gt;one or two posts that talk about it elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;. And they point to the
same answer as mine: &amp;ldquo;yes you can&amp;rdquo;. As a background, I receive a formal education in Information System (which had less computer
science-related courses than computer science or informatics major) and it&amp;rsquo;s
past a decade when I wrote my first &lt;em&gt;Hello World!&lt;/em&gt; program during my first
semester at university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done programming over a decade now. Compared to a decade earlier, now
is relatively easier for someone to learn to code. A lot of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/&#34;&gt;web apps&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codecademy.com/&#34;&gt;built for&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeschool.com/&#34;&gt;this sole purpose&lt;/a&gt; available for either
free or paid by subscription. Moreover, a zillion of tutorials, discussion board and online classes are available
over the internet. However, even with aforementioned resources, learning to
code is still a formidable undertaking. Some will survive and not few won&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I code for living and done many years programming I find myself still
learning to program and to have better craftmanship on programming. I&amp;rsquo;ve been
through the phase from zero to able to write small-course-assignmet programs
to write bit more complex piece of software, and here&amp;rsquo;s some of my thoughts on learning to code based on those experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;perseverance-is-a-must:832af4bab778639ada7945e8314a1044&#34;&gt;Perseverance is a must&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning to code can be fun at the beginning. Solving small problems keeps us
going. However, when we getting closer to real world problems, we might
stumble upon problems that are really hard to solve. We spend hours or even
days to work on it but to no avail. This is where perseverance play its part
&amp;mdash; to keep trying until the problem is solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;google-is-your-best-companion:832af4bab778639ada7945e8314a1044&#34;&gt;Google is your best companion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily Google, any search engine will do. In fact, I use
&lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/&#34;&gt;duckduckgo&lt;/a&gt; most of the time. Believe me, we are not
the only one who have the unsolved problems. A lot of programmers are struggling with the same problems as well and most of the case they have already have the answers. Hence a skill to search on a search engine is a
necessity when programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;focus-don-t-get-distracted:832af4bab778639ada7945e8314a1044&#34;&gt;Focus, don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, this one is rather hard for me, to focus on completing
one thing at a time. Programming could easily overwhelm someone as there
are a lot of information need to digest. Therefore, it is best to have a
plan when we learn programming of any new programming languages. Learn the
basic first, don&amp;rsquo;t be tempted to learn advance stuff at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;get-the-fundamentals:832af4bab778639ada7945e8314a1044&#34;&gt;Get the fundamentals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some may said it is not really important, but the right data structure and algorithm can optimize a program by lot compared to not using any. Knowing fundamentals in computer science can be a clear separation between a bad programmer with a good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;familiarize-with-well-written-projects:832af4bab778639ada7945e8314a1044&#34;&gt;Familiarize with well-written projects&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading and examining well-written open source projects help a lot to benchmark ourself with the best practice out there. We can learn how to properly structure our project, how to make proper comments,
and how to modularize the code. After a while we will find that our code written so far is just a pile of garbage compared to the project. However,
it is a necessary part of learning; we have to know our mistakes to make
improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;sectionsign&#34;
  style=&#34;
    margin:0 auto;
    margin-top: -1rem;
    margin-bottom: 1rem;
    text-align: center;
    letter-spacing: 1em;
    color: #333;
  &#34;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;***&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the end, I believe everyone can code but to be a better programmer requires
one step beyond that, with considerable amount of efforts. Me myself is still
in the middle of voyage to go there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>