<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloudflare on nauval atmaja</title>
    <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/tags/cloudflare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloudflare on nauval atmaja</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://nauvalatmaja.com/tags/cloudflare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Custom Domain for GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/31/setting-up-custom-domain-for-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nauvalatmaja.com/2014/12/31/setting-up-custom-domain-for-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a couple days since &lt;a href=&#34;http://nauvalatmaja.com/&#34;&gt;nauvalatmaja.com&lt;/a&gt; is online,
and to be honest the process was not as hard as I had imagined. Kudos to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://davidensinger.com/&#34;&gt;David Ensinger&lt;/a&gt; who has written in details on
how he &lt;a href=&#34;http://davidensinger.com/2013/03/setting-the-dns-for-github-pages-on-namecheap/&#34;&gt;set up his custom domain for his GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://davidensinger.com/2014/04/transferring-the-dns-from-namecheap-to-cloudflare-for-github-pages/&#34;&gt;tweak it to get faster by using cloudflare&lt;/a&gt;. All
the needed information to do this can be found there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purchased this this domain name at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.namecheap.com/&#34;&gt;NameCheap&lt;/a&gt;, as suggested by David&amp;rsquo;s post,
with just a bit more than five bucks for a year. Then, I used the free plan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloudflare.com&#34;&gt;CloudFlare&lt;/a&gt;
for the DNSs, which I think it is sufficient for my need, and set up the DNS records using &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt;
on the CloudFlare panel to point to my GitHub Pages address. Lastly,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/setting-up-a-custom-domain-with-github-pages/&#34;&gt;I add a &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; file in the root directory of my GitHub Pages repository to redirect it&lt;/a&gt;.
And that&amp;rsquo;s it, practically the process is done after you transfer the DNS from NameCheap to
CloudFlare, you may need to wait for a while to make the changes take effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me less than three hours, more or less, to make my custom domain
accessible. Frankly, I spent more hours thinking the custom domain name I
should use than did the actual setup. I am quite happy with the
setup, hosting static pages on GitHub is right decision. It is simple, easy
and particularly fast, well it&amp;rsquo;s static html pages anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>